## **NAGARAJA M**

#### Web Developer

"A highly motivated and results-driven individual with 1+ years of experience in Backend Development. I am actively seeking a challenging position in an organization where I can utilize my knowledge in software design and development to contribute effectively and continue to grow as a software engineer."



nagarajam98plk@gmail.com

+91-8310054168

P Bengaluru, Karnataka

Portfolio

in LinkedIn

Github

HackerRank

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Backend Developer**

#### **Techfnatic**

m Dec 2022 - Present

P Bengaluru, Karnataka

My journey as a **Backend Developer** at Techfnatic Startup has been an exciting and transformative experience. I've had the privilege of contributing to the development of a wide spectrum of projects from scratch.

- Developed E-Commerce and Point of Sale(POS) Multi-Tenant applications focused on small to medium-sized businesses.
- Developed a Multi-Tenant CRM application focused on small businesses.
- Developed a customized CRM application for Internal usage.
- Worked on the development and maintenance of internal Django websites.

#### Backend Developer - Intern

#### Solar Industries India Ltd.

mar 2022 - Sep 2022

During this internship, I had the opportunity to contribute to the development and enhancement of a **custom ERP system** built using Django Rest Framework (DRF) and Angular. My role focused on fixing bugs, securing APIs, and adding new features to various modules within the ERP system.

- Addressed and resolved various software bugs, thereby elevating the system's stability and performance.
- Contributed to the continual improvement of the system's functionality and overall quality.
- Implemented robust security measures to safeguard APIs, ensuring the protection of sensitive data and interactions.

#### Backend Engineer - Intern

#### **Learn Basics**

Mar 2022 - May 2022

Salem, Tamil Nadu

During this internship, I had the opportunity to work on **content management** projects that allowed me to apply my learned skills in web development and gain hands-on experience. I contributed to the development of two significant projects.

- Developed a comprehensive Flask-based content management application. I
  was responsible for designing and implementing dynamic interfaces using
  HTML/CSS/JavaScript, and building python/flask to manage content
  efficiently.
- Created a robust Django-based web application for course tracking. My role involved crafting user-friendly interfaces, implementing data models, and ensuring smooth interactions for users.

## **EDUCATION**

# Master of Computer Applications BMS College of Engineering

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

#### **HPPC Government First Grade College**

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**



## **LANGUAGES**

English Hindi Telugu Kannada

